我是奥利弗·奎恩
My name is Oliver Queen.
五年里  我被困在地狱一般的小岛上
After five years on a hellish island,
我回来只有一个目标
I have come home with only one goal--
拯救我的城市
to save my city.
但要达到目标  我不能像过去一样成为凶手
But to do so, I can't be the killer I once was.
为了纪念我的朋友  我只能伪装成另一个人
To honor my friend's memory, I must be someone else.
成为另一个存在
I must be something else.
《绿箭》前情回顾
Previously on "Arrow"...
我们一直追踪的一个人
There's a new player we've been tracking.
我们一直叫他丧钟
We've been calling him...Deathstroke.
我有个提议给你们
I have a proposal for you men.
罗伊被注射了血清
Roy was injected with the serum.
还活着  不过我们得看着他
He's alive. But we are going to have to keep an eye on him.
远离西娅
Stay away from Thea.
不  她在你身边的时候非常不安全
No. She's not safe when she's around you.
你爱她  所以你要按我说的做
You love her, and that's why you're going to do what I'm asking.
你怎能不告诉我  马尔科姆·梅林是我父亲
How could you not tell me Malcolm Merlyn was my father?!
我那么信任你
I believed in you.
就在半小时前
As of 30 minutes ago,
你的公司归我了
your company belongs to me.
斯莱德  你为他工作
Slade. You're working for him.
我知道奥利弗·奎恩就是绿箭
I know Oliver Queen is the Arrow.
我觉得这个头套眼睛开孔位置不太对
I don't think my eye holes line up properly.
其他人有这个问题吗
Is anyone else having this problem?
-别紧张  -我就是很紧张
- Don't be nervous. - I'm a lot nervous.
即使对我们而言  这也算是大动作
This is a big move, even for us.
我们曾经利用大动作取得制胜先机
And we've cornered the market on big moves.
斯莱德让我们别无选择
Slade didn't give us any choice.
按照计划而言  这可不是个好主意
Yeah, as far as plans go, this is not a good one.
费利西蒂  这是你的计划
Felicity. This was your plan.
我觉得你其实没批准
I didn't think you'd actually say yes.
我们到了
We're here.
罗伯特·奎恩
应用科学中心
那个人曾经为我工作过
Hey! That man used to work for me.
现在他为我们的敌人工作
And now he works for our enemy.
安保摄像头已经搞定
Security cameras are down.
你们还记得万能钥匙吗
You all remember the skeleton key?
威廉·塔克曼的礼物  就是那个同步信号之王
Courtesy of William Tockman, AKA the Clock King.
可以打开任何锁  包括这一个
It can open any lock. Including this one.
这是我们遇见巴里的地方
This is where we met Barry.
这些是即插即用的
These are plug n' play.
把它们固定在我们说好的地方
Fasten them to what we talked about.
其他的就交给C4炸弹吧
Let the C4 do the rest.
好久没有搞过爆炸了
Been a while since I've blown anything up.
速战速决
Quick and clean.
我是个炸弹客  真不敢相信我成了炸弹客
I'm a bomber. I can't believe I'm a bomber.
不知道能不能当做特殊技能写进简历里
I wonder if I can list that on my resume under special skills.
不许动
Freeze!
我们得走了
We have to go.
热成像显示建筑里已经没人了
Thermal shows everybody's out.
只是一栋建筑  奥利弗
It's just a building, Oliver.
绿箭
第二季第十九集
奎恩集团回应爆炸事件
懦夫
Cowards.
什么人会毫无必要的破坏
Who else would needlessly destroy cutting edge,
尖端科学与医疗技术
scientific and medical technology
而且这些技术
whose sole purpose
是为了把星城变成一个更健康更安全的地方
is to make Starling City a healthier and safer place?
作为奎恩集团的总裁
As CEO of Queen Consolidated,
我要对做下这种恶行的恐怖分子说几句
I have a message to the terrorist who committed this unspeakable act.
你们将被抓住  并接受惩罚
You will be caught, and punished.
我郑重声明  在发现
For the record, I hated her
她是个大坏蛋之前我就很讨厌她
before we found out she was a super villain.
好吧  斯莱德的目的是
Ok. Slade's goal is to create an army
利用米拉库鲁建立一支人体武器部队
of human weapons using the Mirakuru.
为达到这个目的  他需要工业离心机
To do that, he needs an industrial centrifuge.
让伊莎贝尔·罗切夫从你的家族手中
Which having Isabel Rochev steal Queen Consolidated
夺走奎恩集团让他可以大展拳脚
from your family gave him full access to.
但是既然应用科学中心被炸了
But since Applied Sciences went kaboom,
他就没法利用我们的技术
he can't use our technology--
我们以前的技术  来做他的邪恶试验了
well, formerly ours for his warped science experiments.
几周以来斯莱德一直紧紧相逼
Slade has had us on our heels for weeks.
我们跟他正面对决只是时间问题
It's about time we took the fight to him.
我们所做的一切就是为了让他直接面对我们
All this will do is set him back.
我们无法知道下一次攻击会来自哪里
We have no way of knowing where the next attack is coming from.
奥利弗·奎恩回到星城
治安维持者在星城港口枪战
兜帽治安维持者再度来袭
西娅·奎恩被兜帽男所救
听着  你必须放下这事  好吗
Look, you need to drop this, OK?
我没事  真的
I'm fine. Really.
你怎么可能没事
How is any of this fine?
你要把注意力放在自己身上
Look, you need to concentrate on you.
你准备去参加会议吗
Now listen, are you going to your meetings?
是的  我要去那里说说我父亲是怎么入狱的
Yes. It's where I talk about how my father's facing prison.
劳蕾尔
Laurel...
这些都会过去的  好吗  拜托了
This will all blow over, OK? Please.
不  不会的  爸爸
No. It won't, Dad.
你被抓住是因为帮助支持那个治安维持者
You were caught aiding and abetting the Vigilante.
去年跟他一起合作害你丢了警长之职
Working with him last year cost you your detective shield.
现在可能会害你入狱18个月
Now, it can cost you 18 months in prison.
他们想知道他的名字
They want his name.
你知道绿箭是谁吗
Do you know who the Arrow is?
我不知道
I don't.
我发誓
I swear.
那黑衣女子呢
Ok, well, what about the woman in black?
跟绿箭在一起的那个
The one the Arrow works with?
你知道她是谁吗
Do you know who she is?
-不知道  -那你肯定知道些什么吧
- No. - Well, you must have some idea.
宝贝  我没法告诉你我不知道的事
Honey, I can't tell you what I don't know.
时间到
Time's up.
孩子们  照顾好彼此
You girls, you take care of each other.
你真心觉得他不知道绿箭是谁吗
Do you really think he doesn't know who the Arrow is?
爸爸不会撒谎
It's not like dad to lie.
有时最亲近的人  才是最具欺骗性的
Sometimes it's people closest to us who lie to us best.
西娅去哪了
Where is Thea?
她应该也要到场的
She should be here for this, too.
我觉得她不会来了
I doubt she's coming.
我对你们就实话实说了
Well, I can't lie to either of you...
情况很糟糕
it's bad.
一旦伊莎贝尔·罗切夫掌权  就玩完了
If Isabel Rochev is one thing, it's thorough.
为了这次收购  她已经筹划了好几个月
She's been laying the foundation for this takeover for months.
但是我们仍然持有公司大部分股票  对吧
But we still own a majority of stock in the company, correct?
没错  但是伊莎贝尔削弱了股票的价值
Yes, but Isabel has diluted that stock
现在来说  它们分文不值
to the point where it's worthless.
在名义上  你们真的破产了
On paper, you're virtually broke.
那么好消息是什么
And what's the good news?
我们可以保护你们的资产
We can protect your assets.
我们需要把所有的财产
We need to move everything
转移到伊莎贝尔碰不到的地方
into a new trust that Isabel can't touch.
我需要当下所有受惠人的签名
All I need is the beneficiaries from the current trust
来授权此次财产转移
to approve the transfer.
也就是你们两位  还有西娅
The two of you and Thea.
西娅也需要签字
Thea needs to sign off.
没错  而且是马上
Yes. And quickly.
谢谢你  奈德
Thank you, Ned.
现在  我不得不成为市长了
Well, now I have to become mayor.
因为我需要这份工资
It seems I'll need the income.
失去公司  不是你的错
Losing the company wasn't your fault.
是我的错
It was mine.
我败给了伊莎贝尔·罗切夫
I let Isabel Rochev get the better of me.
不是  你总是能看到别人好的一面
No. You always see the good in people,
哪怕他们不值得你如此
even if they don't deserve it.
我比谁都清楚这一点
I know that better than most.
伊莎贝尔报仇心切
Isabel is a vindictive woman.
不管你信任她与否  她都要达到目的
She would have done this with or without your trust.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
你几个月前告诉过我  不能相信她
You told me months ago I couldn't trust her.
你父亲  容易屈服于
Your father had a weakness
美丽  并且强势的女人
for beautiful, strong women.
他们在一起过
They were together?
没错
Yes.
当年她还是商学院的学生
She was still in business school at the time.
美丽的实习生颇受总裁的青睐
The pretty intern that caught the CEO's eye.
你把这个拿给西娅
You take this to Thea,
无论如何说服她  帮助我们反击
and you convince her somehow, to help us fight back.
-能帮我一把吗  -好的
- Will you help me up? - Yeah.
-去我的箱子那  -好的
- Just to my trunk. - Ok.
瞧瞧看谁起来啦
Oh, look who's up.
正好赶上看好戏
Just in time for all the fun.
你要对他做什么
What are you going to do to him?
听听他的尖叫声
Make him scream.
就像他对我们所做的
Just like he made us.
俗话说  活下来就是最好的复仇
They say living well is best revenge?
我觉得折磨才是
I prefer torture.
你想第一个来吗
You want first turn?
不要  拜托
No, please.
我能帮助你们
I can help you.
不  博士  我能帮助你
No, doctor. I can help you.
你说过的  研究需要什么来着
What was it you said you needed for research?
一只眼睛
An eye?
不要
No!
我给你弄一只新鲜的
Let me get you a fresh one.
你们还是可以阻止斯莱德·威尔逊的
You can still stop Slade Wilson!
阿纳托利  慢着
Anatoly. Wait.
你刚刚说什么
What did you say?
我能帮助你们阻止他
I can help you stop him.
怎么阻止  你的神药已经把他变成了怪物
How? That miracle drug has turned him into monster.
我知道  我能让他变回来
I know. I can turn him back.
艾沃  你在说什么
Ivo, what are you saying?!
米拉库鲁  它有解药
The Mirakuru. There's a cure.
西娅在这里吗
Hey, is Thea here?
我没有见到她
No, I haven't seen her.
你爸爸还好吗
How's your dad?
为了绿箭进监狱  他心甘情愿
He's willing to go to jail for the Arrow.
我知道你说不担心
I know you said you weren't worried,
但是狄格和我还是去了罗伊的公寓
but Dig and I went to Roy's apartment.
现在人去楼空
It's empty.
看上去像是几天前就搬走了
Seems like he cleared out a few days ago.
他会去哪呢
Where the hell did he go?
罗伊的事暂时缓一缓
Roy will have to wait.
我们现在要考虑的是斯莱德
We need to deal with Slade,
弄清楚他下一步的行动
figure out what his next move is.
我了解斯莱德
I know Slade.
他不会停手的  除非...
He is not going to stop till...
欢迎回家
Welcome home
你好  莎拉
Hello, Sara.
狄格尔  退后
Diggle, stay back!
你是在浪费子弹
You're wasting your bullets.
小子  别忘了是谁教你打架的
Don't forget who taught you how to fight, kid.
不好意思  我在找我妹妹莎拉·兰斯
Excuse me, I'm looking for my sister, Sara Lance.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我是劳蕾尔·兰斯  我妹妹还好吗
I'm Laurel Lance. Is my sister ok?
她没事的  手腕部有细微骨裂
Oh, she'll be fine. Just a hairline fracture of her wrist.
已经处理过了
We set it.
淤青挺吓人的  看上去以为伤得很重
She's got some nasty bruises, looks worse than it is.
谢谢
Thank you.
与她的旧患相比  这不算什么
Nothing compared to her previous injuries.
什么旧患
Previous...injuries?
是的  你妹妹全身上下
Yes, your sister has extensive scar tissue
都有大量的瘢痕组织
over her entire body.
我上一次见到带有如此多伤痕的人
The last person I saw with that much damage
是一名在伊拉克受伤的退伍军人
was a veteran injured in Iraq.
你妹妹服过役吗
Has your sister served in the military?
没有
No.
她没服过役
No, she hasn't.
莎拉
Sara.
-你来了  -到底发生了什么事
- Hey. - What happened to you?
我没事
Oh, I'm fine.
奥利和我骑摩托车时摔了一下而已
Ollie and I just had a little motorcycle mishap.
没事的
It was nothing.
我已经办好出院手续了
I already got my discharge papers.
但是你的背...
But your back...
那些伤痕  是怎么来的
Those scars, where did you get them?
你没事吧
You OK?
会没事的  你呢
I will be. You?
我也没事  劳蕾尔
Yeah. Yeah. Hi.
你来了  告诉我到底怎么回事
Hi. So tell me what happened.
摩托车祸  笨死了
Motorcycle accident. It was stupid.
我们正要左拐时  一辆车闯了红灯
We were making a left turn, this car ran a red light.
你们录口供了吗
Did you file a police report?
没那个必要  我们俩都没事
We didn't see the point. We're both fine.
这才是最重要的  不是吗
That's-- that's what counts, right?
是
Right.
我真的该走了
I should really go.
一小时后我还要上庭
I have a deposition in an hour.
好的
OK.
谢谢你来看我
Thanks for checking up on me.
当然
Always.
我知道奥利弗·奎恩就是绿箭
I know Oliver Queen is the Arrow.
威登酒吧
你好
Hey.
你昨天没去开会
We missed you yesterday.
跟奈德·福斯特的会
The meeting with Ned Foster.
西娅  我知道你在生我和妈的气
Thea, I know that you're mad at mom and me,
但我们也许有办法解决这次金融危机
but we may have found a way out of this financial mess
我们不会失去一切的
where we aren't going to lose everything.
妈妈和我都签字了  我们...
Mom and I both signed, we just...
我们需要你的签名
We need your signature,
希望能阻止伊莎贝尔毁了我们
and hopefully we can stop Isabel from ruining us.
你是说在你让她毁了我们之后
After you let her ruin us, you mean?
是的
Yeah.
这里说到西娅·奎恩
It says Thea Queen here.
那是谁
Who's she?
就是你  闪电妞
That's you, Speedy.
不是我
No, it's not.
罗伯特·奎恩不是我父亲
Robert Queen wasn't my father.
马尔科姆·梅林才是
Malcolm Merlyn was.
西娅·梅林
Thea Merlyn.
这个名字挺好听的
Kind of has a nice ring to it.
梅林只是你的生父  是老爸养大你的
Merlyn was your biological father, but Dad raised you.
那是因为他不知道我不是他亲生的
Only because he didn't know I wasn't his.
他很爱你的
He...He loved you.
我也是  我仍然还是你哥哥
So do I, and I am still your brother.
你不是  你是我同母异父的哥哥
No, you're not. You're my half brother.
知道我另一个同母异父的哥哥是谁吗
And you know who else was my half brother?
是汤米
Tommy.
我曾经想要吻的那个汤米
Tommy, who I tried to kiss.
我曾经想要吻我同母异父的哥哥
I tried to kiss my half brother--
之后我亲生父亲竟然把他杀了
before my real father killed him!
我的人生就是这么复杂
That's how screwed up I am!
知道吗  最难过的是
And you know the sad part,
之前我的生活竟然要开始渐入佳境了
I was actually starting to be in a good place.
我有间夜店  有罗伊
I had the club, I had Roy,
有个对我说实话的哥哥
I had a brother who wasn't lying to me.
在我混乱的生活中第一次
And for the first time in my crazy life,
所有的一切还算过得去
everything didn't seem so completely and totally messed up.
我还以为我的人生会变好
I thought I was going to be OK.
我实在太蠢了
I'm so stupid.
你一点也不蠢
You're not stupid.
不  我是...
No, what I am...
两个杀人成性的人的女儿
is the daughter of two mass murderers.
不止一个  是两个
Not one, but two.
面对现实吧  奥利
So let's face it, Ollie.
我的人生是不会变好的
I was never going to be OK.
我的基因注定如此
It's not in my genes.
西娅
Thea...
奥利弗
Oliver.
我们现在要讨论安全措施的问题
We need to discuss that security matter now.
情况如何
What do we have?
-斯莱德拿走的东西  -拿走的东西
- What Slade took. - Took?
他不是来杀我们的
He wasn't here to kill us.
他来是因为我们手上有他想要的东西
He was here because we had something that he wanted.
那把万能钥匙
The Skeleto Key.
我做了全面检查  只有这把钥匙不见了
I did a full sweep. It's the only thing that's missing.
现在他需要一种新方式来大规模生产血清
He needs a new way to mass produce the serum now that
因为我们炸毁了应用科学中心
we've dusted Applied Sciences.
拥有万能钥匙
With the Skeleton Key,
他能进入任何地方  拿到任何想要的东西
he can get into anywhere and take anything he wants.
我们知道他想要什么
We know what he wants.
只需要先他一步找到
We just need to find it first.
星城最先进的技术
Where is the most cutting edge technology housed
在哪里
in Starling City?
星级实验室  星城
星级实验室  仓库数据库
这是每个曾在星级实验室
The combined inventory of every scientist
工作过的科学家的数据
who ever worked at S.T.A.R. Labs.
所有的都在这里
All housed right in here.
因为我将这栋大楼命名为"屌炸天"
I hereby christen this building "Da bomb."
现在没人这么说了
Nobody says that anymore.
我就这么说
I say it.
哥就是这么酷
I define my own cool.
我还是难以相信威尔斯博士竟要关掉这个地方
I still can't believe Dr. Wells is shutting this place down.
尖端科研实验室在我们打开粒子加速器时
S.T.A.R. Labs blew a hole in Central City
在中心城市内引起了大爆炸
when we turned the particle accelerator on.
星城要终止
It's not surprising that
对这个设施的租赁也在情理之中
Starling City cancelled the lease on this facility.
"让我们来保管社区内无人管理的样机吧"
We're not exactly the poster children for
我们这么说了  但却没有做到
"Let us store our unregulated prototypes in your neighborhood."
那是个意外  凯特琳
It was an accident, Caitlin.
跟受害者家属
Yeah, well, try telling
也这么说试试看吧
that to the families of the people who died.
或许你应该先想想怎么给自己一个交代
Maybe you can figure out how to tell that to yourself.
西斯科  把库存盘点完  我们就能回家了
Look, Cisco, let's get this inventory done so we can go home.
我以为这里没别人了
I thought we were the only ones here...
或许是其中一个警卫
Maybe it's one of the security guards.
你好啊
Oh. Hey, man.
我们马上就能结束了
We should be wrapped up any minute now.
你有没有一种不祥的预感
Are you getting a bad vibe off this guy?
你让我追你的时间越长
The longer you make me chase you,
我折磨你的时间就越长
the slower I will kill you.
帮帮我
Help me.
这个设备本属于亚瑟·莱特
This equipment belonged to Arthur Light.
威尔斯两年前把他炒了
Wells fired him two years ago.
-为什么  -因为他是个疯子
- Why? - Because he was a psycho.
你可千万要搞定这东西啊
Please tell me you can make this work.
禁区  只有特准人员可进
我收回我刚说的话
I take back what I said--
我会速战速决的
I'll make this quick.
不
No!
我们来晚了
We're too late.
-费利西蒂  -西斯科  凯特琳
- Felicity! - Cisco, Caitlin!
你们还好吗  他没伤害你们吧  他没有吧
Are you guys ok? He didn't hurt you, did he?
你说了两次"他"
You said "he" twice.
你知道袭击我们的人是谁吗
Do you know who attacked us?
那个戴着面具手拿长剑的疯子
That lunatic with the mask and the sword?
不  我不知道
Uh, no. I--no, I don't know.
我说了两遍"他"  因为我听到广播里说
I--I said "he" twice, because on the radio,
袭击你们的那个人有男性特征
I heard that the person who attacked you had man parts,
所以我认为他是个男的
which would make him a...he.
我叫约翰·狄格尔  奎恩联合企业的保安
I'm John Diggle, I work security for Queen Consolidated.
你知道面具男拿走什么了吗
Do you have any idea what the masked man may have taken?
比如一台工业离心机之类的
an industrial centrifuge, by any chance?
无可奉告  这是个秘密
No. It's a secret.
什么样的秘密
What kind of secret?
不能说的秘密
The kind I have to keep.
西斯科也得保守这个秘密吗
Well, does Cisco have to keep it, too?
-没错  -好吧
- Yes. He does. - Ok.
我们很高兴看到你们俩都没事
We're just so happy that you guys are ok.
巴里怎么样了
How's Barry doing?
老样子
He's the same.
巴里的情况恶化了
Barry's condition deteriorated.
他们把他移到了尖端科技研究实验室内照顾他
They moved him to S.T.A.R. Labs. They've been looking after him.
我就是因此而认识西斯科和凯特琳的
That's how I met Cisco and Caitlin.
是的
Right.
我一有空就会再去看他的
Well, I'll come visit again, as soon as I can.
那很好
That would be cool.
别担心  很多人都来看巴里
Don't worry, Barry gets lots of visitors.
艾丽丝经常去那儿
Iris is there a lot.
艾丽丝吗
Iris?
她是
She's, um,
他的
his...
某人
Something.
原来如此
Oh.
那好吧
Sure. Good.
真了不起
That's just swell.
巴里还在昏迷中就已经有进展了
Barry's in a coma and he's already moved on.
我侵入了哈里森·威尔斯的个人档案
I hacked into Harrison Wells' personal files.
他是尖端科技研究实验室的主管
He's the director S.T.A.R. Labs,
所以这差不多让我可以查看任何资料
which basically makes me unstoppable.
看看我发现了什么
And look what I found.
这是他们其中一个生物技术项目的原型
It's a prototype for one of their new bio-tech projects.
还没有申请到专利
The patent is still pending,
或许这就是为什么他们不想告诉我们
which is probably why they didn't
那到底是什么东西
want to tell us what it was.
所以这到底是什么
So what is it?
这是个生物传输导管
It's a biotransfuser.
它可以同时把血液从一个病人体内
It can deliver blood from one single patient
输入到多个病人体内
into multiple patients, at once.
为什么斯莱德需要输血
Why would Slade need a blood transfusion?
他不需要
He doesn't.
但他为了创建自己的私人军队
The prisoners that he freed from Iron Heights last week
上周从铁山监狱放走的那些囚犯需要
to create his own personal army do.
稍作调整  斯莱德就可以将它改造
With a few tweaks, Slade can retro-fit it for the Mirakuru,
用于米拉库鲁  而且他完全不用顾忌
bypassing what we know to be a less than desirable
失败之后死亡率很高的问题
ratio of success to, you know, death.
这一切都将会在机器内进行
Instead of it metabolizing in the person,
而不是利用人体内新陈代谢
it happens in the machine.
这得需要大量的血液才行啊
That's going to require a whole lot of blood.
即使耐力非凡的斯莱德
Even a man with Slade's stamina
也承受不住那种血液流干的痛苦
can't handle that kind of drain.
-很好  -你什么意思
- Good. - What do you mean?
我们就让他使用
We let him use it.
他会变得虚弱  不堪一击
He'll be weak, vulnerable,
那时候就是我杀死他的好时机
and that will be my opportunity to kill him.
我们怎么才能找到这个东西
How do we find this thing?
要启动这样的机器
A machine like this pulls an exorbitant
需要大量的电力支持
amount of power from the grid.
当它启动时  我就会知道时间和地点
When it turns on, I'll know when and where.
现在  我们只能静心等待
Right now, we just wait.
我受够无尽等待了
I'm tired of waiting.
别听他的  他在撒谎
Don't listen to him, he's lying!
解药真的存在  我保证
The cure is real, I promise!
不  他只是想要活命才会这么说的
No, he's just trying to save his neck.
安东尼  看着我
Anthony, look at me.
告诉我们解药的事
Tell us about the cure.
我想帮助你  莎拉
I want to help you, Sara.
但首先  你要保证你也会帮我
But first, you have to promise you'll help me, too.
她救不了你的命
She can't save your life.
没有人可以的
No one can, not anymore.
我只求一个痛快
All I ask is for is a quick death.
你不配那么快解脱
You don't deserve a quick death.
我明白
I know.
但我依然请求你们
And I'm still asking.
这是你的决定
It's your call.
谢谢
Thank you.
快从实说来  艾沃
Start talking, Ivo!
我从来没有成功地
I was never able to replicate the Mirakuru serum
从我发现的二战时期日本的研究中
from the original Japanese World War II
复制出米拉库鲁血清
research I discovered.
经过一年的
After conducting experiments
人体试验之后
on the prisoners that I acquired this past year,
我成功合成了一种溶液
I was able to synthesize a solution
能够抵消和逆转
that counteracts, reverses
米拉库鲁所产生的生理效应
the physiological effects that exposure to Mirakuru produces.
从拥有超人的能力
From more than human...
转变回普通人类
back to human.
解药现在在哪里
Where is this cure now?
你会信守诺言结束我的生命吗
You'll keep your word about ending my life?
对  快告诉我们
Yes. Tell us.
在货船上
On the freighter.
在我房间的保险柜里
In the safe in my quarters.
我想
Now I believe...
我的这部分已经做完了
this concludes my end of our deal.
不管你要说什么  反正一分钟内
Whatever you came here to say, it takes security
保安就会上来
about 60 seconds to reach this floor,
所以我就陪你聊一会
so I would start talking.
斯莱德在哪里
Where's Slade?
我只是给你机会做正确的事
I just wanted to give you the chance to do the right thing.
我不到30岁
I'm under 30,
担任着财富500强企业的总裁
and I'm the CEO of a Fortune 500 company.
我想这足以说明我做了正确的事
I'd say I've already done the right thing.
你知道斯莱德·威尔逊是什么样的人吗
And do you even know who Slade Wilson is?
或者他做这些是为了什么
Or why he's doing this?
我不在乎
I don't care.
-这些都是我应得的  -你应得的
- I got what I earned. - What you earned?
你以为上了我爸爸的床
You think that sleeping with my father
他的公司就应该属于你了吗
entitles you to my family's company?
你根本不知道是怎么回事
You have no idea what you're talking about.
他玩过不少女人
Wow, he fooled around with a lot of girls.
其他人可没有来恶意收购的
I don't see any of them ordering hostile takeovers.
玩女人
Fooled around?
你妈是这么跟你说的吗
Is that what your mother told you?
她当然会把我说成一个无关紧要的小三
Of course she would write me off as a meaningless affair.
斯莱德·威尔逊让我吃了很大的苦
Slade Wilson put me through hell.
他的魔鬼训练差点害死了我
His training nearly killed me.
如果我只是个被抛弃的情人
Would I put myself through
我何必要去承受这些
all that just because I was a jilted lover?
说实话  我不知道你算什么
Honestly, I don't know what you are!
我是你父亲的挚爱
I was your father's soul mate.
他当时已经准备离开你母亲
He was going to leave your mother,
离开公司  丢下你
leave the company, leave you.
-我们行李都整理好了  -是吗
- Our bags were packed. - Really?
可你妹妹偏偏要摔坏胳膊
Your sister had to go and break her arm
做出些蠢事来
doing something ridiculous, no doubt.
她从马背上摔下来了
She fell off her horse.
他接到电话的时候我们已经到机场了
We were at the airport when he got the call.
我求他不要回去
I begged him not to go.
我提醒他西娅甚至不是他亲生的
I reminded him that Thea wasn't even his.
你是说我爸爸早就知道
Are you saying that my father knew?
他当然知道了
Of course he knew.
他是傻  但不是白痴
He was a fool, not an idiot.
就像傻瓜一样  他还是很疼爱她
And like a fool, he loved her anyway.
他答应我第二天就离开
He promised me that we would leave the next day.
可恰恰相反  我的实习被终止了
But instead, my internship was terminated
他也再没跟我说过一句话
and he never spoke to me again.
你就是为了这个吧
Oh, so that's what this is really about.
他为了我们抛弃了你
He chose us over you.
请把奎恩先生请出大楼
Please escort Mr. Queen off the premises.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
不要让他再进这座大楼了
He's no longer welcome in this building.
这是我的地方
My building.
喂
Hello?
西娅  我是奥利
Thea, it's Ollie.
我想和你见面谈  就五分钟
Listen, I just need five minutes face to face.
你想干什么
What do you want?
有件事情需要告诉你
There's something you need to hear.
就五分钟  酒吧关门后来吧
Five minutes. Come by the club after we close.
刚跟费利西蒂通过话
Just spoke with Felicity.
有人要找绿箭
Someone reached out to the Arrow.
见面谈谈
Wants a meeting.
是谁
Who?
劳蕾尔
Laurel.
待地舒服吗  兰斯警官
You comfortable in there, Officer Lance?
如果你冷的话我可以给你再找条毯子
I can see if there's an extra blanket if you're cold.
我很好  既然我现在关在这里了
I'm good. But hey, now that I'm on this side of the bars,
你叫我昆汀就行了
I think it's just Quentin.
我相信这只是个误会
I'm sure it's just a misunderstanding.
你很快就能出去了
You'll be out of here soon.
谢谢你的乐观
Yeah, I appreciate your optimism.
你在干什么
Hey, what are you doing?
伙计
Hey, buddy.
警官  快来人啊  快来人啊
Officer! We need help! We need help!
你要干什么  伙计
Whoa, whoa, what are you doing, man?
记得我吗
Remember me?
你该记得的  因为我记得你  警官
You should, 'cause I remember you, Officer.
不  你不能这么做
No, you can't do this.
没事的  别紧张
All right, take it easy.
就是因为你和那个穿帽衫的怪胎
'Cause you and that hooded freak show
我才进了这鬼地方
are the reason I'm in this place.
我觉得我应该过来招呼你一下
I thought I should be the one to welcome you.
这还没完
This isn't over!
这没完
This is not over!
我听说你父亲被捕了
I heard about your father being arrested.
如果我可以的话我会帮他的
If I could help him, I would.
我不是为了这件事叫你来的
That's not what this is about.
很有趣不是吗
It's funny, isn't?
一年以前他以为你是个谋杀犯
A year ago, he thought you were a murderer.
而我  我却被你吸引
And me, I was-- I was drawn to you.
我也不知道这是为什么  但
I couldn't explain why, but...
但是我总觉得我们心灵相通
but a part of me felt connected to you.
你总是会及时地出现
You were always there.
为了我
For me...
为了我的家人
for my family,
而因为某种原因我从来没问过为什么
and for some reason, I never asked why.
你现在是在问我吗
Are you asking now?
不需要了
I don't have to.
因为我已经知道答案了
Because I already know the answer.
喂
Hello?
爸爸出事了
It's dad.
发生什么了
What is it?
劳蕾尔  我真的很抱歉
Laurel, I am so sorry.
你父亲现在处于保护性监禁
We had your father under protective custody.
在铁山监狱根本就没有保护性监禁可言
There's no such as thing as protective custody in Iron Heights.
爸爸
Dad!
我没事的  宝贝  我没事
It's all right, sweetheart, it's all right.
别 别 别碰我的肋骨
Hey, whoa, don't touch the ribs! The ribs.
我快要厌倦来医院看我的家人了
I'm getting tired of visiting my family members in a hospital.
发生什么了
What happened?
只不过是一个老相识过来拜访我一下
Oh, it's just some old collar paid me a visit.
我想我在监狱里不太受欢迎
I guess I'm not the most popular guy in prison.
莎拉  你介意我和爸爸单独聊聊吗
Sara, do you mind giving Dad and I a second alone, please?
当然不
Yeah, of course.
我就在外面等着
I'll be right outside.
别走太远  宝贝
Don't go far, sweetie.
爸爸
Dad...
怎么了  宝贝
What is it, honey?
-我必须要告诉你一件事  -怎么了
- I have to tell you something. - What is it?
我知道绿箭是谁了
I know who the Arrow is.
什么
What?
不要讲出来
Don't say another word.
不要说
Don't say anything.
好吧
Ok.
听着  我曾经宁愿不当警察
Listen to me, there was a time when I would have
也要找出他的真实身份  你知道的
sold out my badge to find out his name. You know that.
但是现在我意识到我已经不在乎了
But then I realize I didn't care who he was.
事实上  我甚至不想知道他是谁了
In fact, I didn't even want to know who he was.
为什么
Why not?
因为我明白一旦我知道了他是谁
'Cause I knew if I knew who he really was,
他就成为了一个真实的人
then he'd become a person, right?
也许他也有家人和朋友
Maybe he's got a family. Friends.
有在乎他的人
People that care about him.
他也有自己的生活
Someone with a life.
那样他就不是我需要他成为的样子了
That he couldn't be what I needed him to be.
不是这个城市需要他成为的样子了
What this city needs him to be.
绿箭这个角色才重要
It's the Arrow that matters.
帽衫下面的人是谁无所谓
The man under the hood isn't important.
你能想像他的生活是什么样的吗
Can you imagine what it's like to be him?
他日复一日的生活
What he has to live with day in and day out,
必须是什么样子的
what that's got to be like.
我能做的就是坐在这里给他一些时间
The least I can do is sit here and do a little bit of time for him.
你父亲怎么样了
How's your father?
如果你放弃对他的指控
He'll be better once you drop all charges
在释放文件上签字那他就更好了
and sign his release papers.
他面临的可是一年半的监禁
He is facing 18 months.
没错  不过他不会再待在监狱里了
Yes. But he is not going to stay here another day
除非你想让我辞职
unless you want me to resign
然后开始我的刑事辩护律师生涯
and embark on an exciting new career as a criminal defense attorney
我唯一的志向就是起诉地方检察官办公室
whose sole ambition will be to sue the District Attorney's office
非法逮捕和怠忽致危罪
for wrongful arrest and reckless endangerment.
你父亲签了保证书之后
Your father will be released on his own recognizance
一小时之内就会被释放
within the hour.
明天开始复职
And reinstated. Tomorrow.
给你一个建议
A word of advice--
以后要小心选择你的对手
be mindful of the battles you choose,
因为不是所有争斗都像今天这么容易
because it will not always be this easy.
法律顾问干得漂亮
Nice work, counselor.
谢谢
Thank you.
你的胳膊怎么样了
How's your arm?
还可以  只有挥手的时候才疼
Fine. Only hurts when I wave.
我没事的  向你保证
I'm fine, I promise.
我知道你会没事的
I know you will be.
谢谢
Thanks.
威登酒吧
谢谢你能同意来和我谈谈
Thank you for agreeing to talk to me.
我只是负责来听你说的
You're talking. I only agreed to listen.
我只是想说
I just want to start with--
我知道你认为
I know you think that--
等等
Hold on.
费利西蒂  我现在没时间接电话
I can't talk right now, Felicity.
我明白  但是柯林斯梅因电网数据突增
I know. But the grid at Collins and Main just spiked,
显示为用电量巨大
drawing a hell of a lot of power,
这意味着要么有人正在使用
which means someone either
这个世界上最大的吹风机
plugged in the world's largest hair dryer,
要不就是生物疏导器已经开始运行
or the biotransfuser just went online.
这台机器有特定的动力循环周期
The power cycle on this machine is very specific.
你有三十分钟时间  最多四十分钟
You have 30 minutes, 40 tops.
我知道这很自私  奥利弗
I know this is selfish, Oliver,
不要怪我这么说
and don't hate me for saying this,
但是  你别去
but...don't go.
如果西娅不在那些文件上签字
If you don't get Thea to sign those documents,
你们家就会失去所有财产
your family loses all of its assets.
如果我不马上阻止斯莱德
If I don't stop Slade right now,
会有更多人失去更多财产
a lot of people will lose a lot more.
我要是你的话我可不会碰
I wouldn't touch that if I were you.
在运行中动他会害死他的
Removing him mid-cycle will surely end his life.
-斯莱德  他只是个孩子  -他来这里
- Slade, he's just a kid! - Who's here
是因为你把他拒之门外了
only because you pushed him away.
他之前敬仰的一直是你
You were the one person he looked up to.
可是  你却伤害了他的心灵
And for that, you crushed his soul.
我们在布鲁德海文的一处避难所找到他的
We found him at a shelter in Bludhaven.
太可怜了  连抵抗都没有抵抗
Pathetic. Didn't even put up a fight.
我会抵抗的
I will.
告诉我怎么关掉
Tell me how to shut it down.
如果你能感受到我体内汹涌的能量
If you could feel the power that is surging through me...
你就会知道我不怕一只小小的箭
You would know that I do not fear an arrow.
我远比你想象的要强大的多
I am stronger than you can even imagine.
马上...
And soon...
就会有人跟我一样了
I will not be alone.
你伤害不了我  小子
You can't hurt me, kid.
罗伊  来  坚持住
Come on, Roy. All right, stay with me.
他失血过多
He's lost a lot of blood.
我不知道生物输液对他造成了什么影响
I don't know what the biotransfuser did to him.
但是他的脉搏很虚弱  几乎没有呼吸了
But his pulse is really weak; He's barely breathing.
他需要真正的医生
And he needs a real doctor.
不能带他去医院  医院会做各种检查
We can't take him to a hospital-- they run tests.
不能让别人知道他体内有什么东西
We need to keep what's in him from getting out.
那我们该怎么办
What do we do now?
我们就只能等着
The only thing we can do-- we wait.
与此同时  斯莱德的问题还没有解决
Well, while we're waiting, we still have a Slade problem.
他还有20个跟他一样的人
He's got 20 guys just like him,
我们没办法阻止他
and we have no way to stop him.
不  我们有办法
Yes, we do.
那是我想的东西吗
Is that what I think it is?
米拉库鲁
Mirakuru.
你不会是想服下这个吧
You weren't thinking about taking it, were you?
不是
No.
我们要用它制造解药
We're going to use it to make a cure.
奥利弗  我们都不知道
Oliver, we don't even know
它的作用是不是可逆的
if it's possible to reverse the affects.
我们知道
Yes, we do.
艾沃成功过
Ivo did it.
你怎么不早说  奥利弗
Why didn't you ever tell us that, Oliver?
因为我感觉很惭愧
Because I'm ashamed.
为什么
Of what?
五年前  我有机会给斯莱德用解药的
Five years ago, I had the chance to use the cure on Slade.
可我却选择了杀他
I chose to kill him.
现在的一切都是我的错
Everything that's happening right now is my fault.
我救过你一次  莎拉
I saved you once, Sara.
感觉像很久以前的事了
It feels like a long time ago now.
你是时候回报我了
Time to return the favor.
可能你们不会相信
You might not believe it now,
但我以前是个好人
but I was considered a good man.
是个好医生  好丈夫
A good doctor. A good husband.
可后来米拉库鲁把我变疯了
Until the Mirakuru drove me mad.
我甚至没有让自己...
I didn't even take any myself--
你没必要为我这么做的
You didn't have to do that for me.
一旦你杀了人
Once you take a life...
它会永远改变你的
it changes you forever.
我不想让你那样
And I don't want that for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
幸运儿
Schastlivchik.
我们现在怎么办
So, now what do we do?
你们应该不会有人知道怎么开潜艇吧
Well, I don't suppose any of you know how to pilot a submarine?
西娅
Thea.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
收拾东西而已  我觉得
Just grabbing some stuff. Something tells me
这里的新主人不想让我的衣服出现在这里
the mansion's new owner won't want my clothes here.
西娅  等等
Thea, wait.
现在你不忙了啊
Now he's not busy.
对不起  我也无能为力
I'm so sorry, that couldn't be helped.
现在我能跟你说几句话吗
May I speak to you now?
爸爸知道真相
Dad knew the truth.
什么
What?
他知道梅林的事
He knew about Merlyn.
怎么可能
How?
他从没跟我提过
He never said anything to me.
没这个必要
He didn't have to.
西娅  不论爸爸有什么错
Thea, whatever dad's faults were...
他都是爱我们的
He loved us.
爱我们所有人
All of us.
因为我们是他的家人
Because we were his family.
你是他女儿
You were his daughter,
一次破验血不会改变这点
and some stupid blood test wasn't going to change that.
他选择了我们
He chose us.
他选择了你
He chose you.
他决定
He made a decision
做你的父亲
to be your father,
即使他并不是非这样不可
even though he didn't have to be.
所以你有什么感想呢
So what does that tell you?
感想就是他是个骗子
It tells me that he's a liar.
就跟你们俩一样
Just like both of you.
星城实验室
我需要你们帮我个忙
I need you guys to do me a favor.
记得保密
This time, it'll be our secret.
威登酒吧
奥利弗
Oliver.
这是干什么
What's this for?
因为你对我而言很重要
Because you're important to me.